rootsaction.org 2018-11-19

# Privacy Policy - RootsAction

**Updated 1/18/2011**

Roots Action, the primary* website operated by Action for a Progressive Future (APF), is committed to protecting the privacy and security of visitors to our website. Outlined below is our online privacy policy for information collected through our websites and email lists.

Privacy of our email lists

Roots Action considers your contact information to be private and confidential. We will NOT disclose it to any other entity unless you specifically authorize us to do so.

By providing your name and contact information on an action campaign, you are authorizing us to send your contact information—along with your own correspondence—to the people specifically targeted in that action campaign (e.g. elected officials, decision-makers, journalists, etc.).

If you support Roots Action—and share your personally identifying information—this information will be used only to provide you with more targeted content, send further information about our organization, or contact you when necessary.

We will email you with occasional updates and opportunities for action. We will do our best to respect your time and attention. You may always opt out of receiving future emails, and simple instructions on how to remove yourself will be included in any email you receive.

Our system allows users to send messages to their contacts about the work that RootsAction is doing. However, we do not collect or store personally identifying information (such as email addresses) that users divulge about other people while using tools (such as a tell-a-friend feature) on our site.

We strongly recommend that you do not post confidential information to any unconstrained data fields—such as comment areas—on this site.

Resale or disclosure of information to third parties

We do not share or otherwise disclose any personal information, including your name, address or email addresses with other organizations. Only Roots Action staff and our authorized agents have access to personally identifiable information provided by visitors to our site.

Disclosure for legal reasons

We may release personal information to third parties: (1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, valid governmental requests, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (2) to prevent, investigate, detect, or prosecute criminal offenses or attacks on the integrity of the website or our network; and/or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Action For a Progressive Future, the users of the website, you, or the public. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your personal information to a third party, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order.

Browser information collected on our website

As with any website operator, Roots Action analyzes our website logs to constantly improve the value of our website. We use an external service to provide real-time reporting to us and our authorized agents of browser accesses to our site. This reporting includes page views, unique views, unique visitors, repeat visitors, frequency of visits, and peak-volume traffic periods. We do not use this service to gather, request, record, require, collect or track any Internet users' personally identifiable information.

Personalization of Content

We use cookies on our site to personalize and customize the experience of our visitors and to support some necessary functions. We also use cookies to better understand how our visitors use our site. You have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. For more information on how to modify your browser settings to block or filter cookies, refer to [this site](http://www.cookiecentral.com/faq/).

However, please note that if you reject some or all cookies, your experience at this and on other sites throughout the Internet may not be complete. In addition, if you do not allow cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of personalized content delivery offered by us or other Internet sites.

Security

We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving financial data from our site. We use industry-standard methods to protect the confidentiality and integrity of personal information. While there is no such thing as "perfect security" anywhere on the Internet, we protect your data just as we protect our own. Furthermore, access to personal data is restricted within the company, and all employees are aware that personal data is private.

Linking

Throughout our website, we provide links to other websites which may contain information of interest to our readers. We take no responsibility for, and exercise no control over, the organizations, views, or accuracy of the information contained on other websites. Please note: When you click on links to other websites, we encourage you to read their privacy policies. Their standards may differ from ours and we are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other websites.

Changes to this Privacy Policy

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice.

Each version of this Policy will be identified at the top of the page by its effective date.

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy or its implementation, you may contact us using the contact information on the About Us page. We strive to respond to all inquiries within one week.

* This privacy policy applies to all websites operated by Action for a Progressive Future.
